（屏幕呼啸）
(screen whooshing)
（贴纸弹出）
(sticker popping)
（屏幕呼啸）
(screen whooshing)
- 在这段视频中，我们来看看
- In this video, we take a look
在称为困惑度的神秘测深指标上。
at the mysterious sounding metric called perplexity.
你可能遇到过困惑
You might have encountered perplexity
在阅读生成模型时。
when reading about generative models.
你可以在这里看到两个例子，
You can see two examples here,
一张来自原始变压器纸，
one from the original transformer paper,
“你需要的只是注意力，”
"Attention is all you need,"
另一篇来自最近的 GPT-2 论文。
and the other one from the more recent GPT-2 paper.
困惑度是衡量绩效的常用指标
Perplexity is a common metric to measure the performance
的语言模型。
of language models.
它的值越小，性能越好。
The smaller its value, the better the performance.
但它究竟意味着什么，我们又该如何计算呢？
But what does it actually mean and how can we calculate it?
机器学习中非常常见的量
A very common quantity in machine learning
是可能性。
is the likelihood.
我们可以计算可能性
We can calculate the likelihood
作为每个标记概率的乘积。
as the product of each token's probability.
这意味着对于每个令牌，
What this means is that for each token,
我们使用语言模型来预测它的概率
we use the language model to predict its probability
基于之前的标记。
based on the previous tokens.
最后，我们将所有概率相乘
In the end, we multiply all probabilities
得到的可能性。
to get the likelihood.
有可能，
With the likelihood,
我们可以计算另一个重要的量，
we can calculate another important quantity,
交叉熵。
the cross-entropy.
您可能已经听说过交叉熵
You might have already heard about cross-entropy
在查看损失函数时。
when looking at loss function.
它通常用作分类中的损失函数。
It is often used as a loss function in classification.
在语言建模中，我们预测下一个标记
In language modeling, we predict the next token
基于之前的令牌，
based on the previous token,
这也是一个分类任务。
which is also a classification task.
因此，如果我们想计算
Therefore, if we want to calculate
一个例子的交叉熵，
the cross-entropy of an example,
我们可以简单地将它传递给模型
we can simply pass it to the model
以其输入作为标签。
with its inputs as labels.
然后损失对应于交叉熵。
The loss then corresponds to the cross-entropy.
我们现在只差一个手术了
We are now only a single operation away
从计算困惑度。
from calculating the perplexity.
通过对交叉熵取幂，我们得到了困惑。
By exponentiating the cross-entropy, we get the perplexity.
所以你看到困惑是密切相关的
So you see that the perplexity is closely related
到损失。
to the loss.
插入以前的结果
Plugging in previous results
表明这相当于求幂
shows that this is equivalent to exponentiating
每个令牌的负平均锁定概率。
the negative average lock probability of each token.
请记住，损失只是一个弱代理
Keep in mind that the loss is only a weak proxy
用于模型生成高质量文本的能力
for a model's ability to generate quality text
困惑也是如此。
and the same is true for perplexity.
出于这个原因，人们通常也计算
For this reason, one usually also calculates
更复杂的指标
more sophisticated metrics
例如生成任务上的 BLEU 或 ROUGE。
such as BLEU or ROUGE on generative tasks.
（屏幕呼啸）
(screen whooshing)